In this video we're going to begin our discussion of formal operational semantics.
在这段视频中，我们将开始讨论正式的操作语义。
Just as we did with lexical analysis, parsing and type-checking. The first step
就像我们处理词法分析、解析和类型检查一样。第一步
in defining what we mean by a formal operational semantics is introduced the
在定义我们所说的正式操作语义时，引入了
notation and it turns out that the notation we want to use for operational
表示法，结果是我们想要用于运算的表示法
semantics is the same or very similar in the notation we use in type-checking. We
语义与我们在类型检查中使用的符号相同或非常相似。我们
are going to be using logical rule of inference. So, in the case of
将使用逻辑推理规则。所以，在这种情况下
type-checking, the kinds of inference rules we, we presented, proofing's of the
类型检查，我们，我们提出的各种推理规则，
forms that in some context. We could show that some expression had a particular type
在某种背景下形成了这一点。我们可以证明某些表达式具有特定类型
in this case to type c. And for evaluation we're going to be doing something quite
在本例中，键入c。对于求值，我们将做一些相当大的工作
similar. We will show that in some contacts now that this is going to be a
差不多。我们将在一些联系人中展示，现在这将是一个
different kind of context that we had in typing so this is going to be an
不同的上下文，我们在打字时有，所以这将是一个
evaluation context as oppose to a type context and so what goes in the context
与类型上下文相对的求值上下文，以及上下文中的内容
will actually be different. But for the moment all that really matters is there is
实际上会有所不同。但就目前而言，真正重要的是
some kind of a context and in that context we're going to be able to show some
某种上下文，在这种上下文中，我们将能够展示一些
expression evaluates to a particular value b. So as an example, let's take a look at
表达式的计算结果是一个特定值b。
this simple expression, e1 + e2 and let's say that using our rules which we, I
这个简单的表达式，e1+e2，假设使用我们的规则，我们，我
haven't shown you yet, but let's say we had a bunch of rules and we could show in
我还没有向你们展示，但是让我们假设我们有一堆规则，我们可以展示
the initial context. That e1 in that same context, okay? So these context are going
初始上下文。这个E1在同样的背景下，好吗？所以这些背景是
to be the same, that e1 evaluated to the a value of five and e2 also in that same
为了相同，e1评估为a值5，e2也在该相同中评估为a值
context evaluated to the value of, of seven then we could prove that e1 + e2
上下文评估为7的值，那么我们可以证明e1+e2
evaluated to the value of twelve. If you think about it what this rule was saying
估值为十二。如果你想一想这条规则说的是什么
is that if e1 evaluates to five and e2 evaluates to seven, then if you evaluated
如果e1求值为5，e2求值为7，那么如果你求值
the expression e1 + e2, you're going to get the value twelve. And what's the
表达式e1+e2，你会得到值12。还有什么是
context doing, well it doesn't do a whole lot in this particular rule. But remember
上下文操作，在这个特定的规则中，它并没有做很多事情。但请记住
what the context was for in type checking. The context was for giving values to the
类型检查中上下文的用途。上下文用于将值赋给
free variables of the expression. And so, we need for an expres sion like e1 + e2 to
表达式的自由变量。因此，我们需要像e1+e2这样的表达式
say something about what the values are, the variable that might appear in e1 and
说说这些值是什么，可能出现在e1和e1中的变量
in e2 in order to say what they evaluate to and, and therefore, to say what the
在e2中，为了说出他们的评估结果，因此，也就是说，
entire expression e1 + e2 will evaluated to. Now, let's be a little more precise
整个表达式e1+e2的计算结果为。现在，让我们再精确一点
about what's going to go in the context. So, let's consider the evaluation of a, a
关于在上下文中会发生什么。那么我们来考虑一下对一个，一个
expression or statement like y gets x+1. Okay, so we are going to assign y the
像y这样的表达式或语句得到x+1。好的，我们要给y赋值
value x+1 and there are two things that we have to know in order to evaluate this
值x+1，我们必须知道两件事才能评估它
expression. First of all, we have to know where In memory of valuable start. So, for
表达式。首先，我们要知道有价值的记忆是从哪里开始的。所以，对于
example, the variable x here, we're going to have to go and look up excess value and
例如，这里的变量x，我们将不得不去查找超额值，
then add one to it And then that value is going to be stored in whatever memory
然后将其加1，然后该值将存储在任何内存中
location holds the value for y okay so there is a mapping from variables, Two
位置保存y的值，好的，所以有一个来自变量的映射，两个
memory locations. Okay and that is called, In operational semantics the environment
内存位置。好的，在操作语义学中，这叫做环境
and this is a little confusing maybe because it use environment for other
这有点令人困惑，可能是因为它将环境用于其他
things. Okay, so now let's forget about, as all we uses of the word environment. We
一些事情。好了，现在让我们忘掉环境这个词，因为我们使用的都是环境这个词。我们
were talking about the operational semantics, what the environment means is
我们谈论的是操作语义，环境的含义是
the mapping, the association in between variables and where that variable store in
变量之间的映射、关联以及变量的存储位置
memory. And then in addition, we're going to need a store and that's going to tell
记忆。此外，我们还需要一家商店，这将说明
us what is in the memory. So just knowing the location for a variable isn't quite
我们的记忆里有什么。所以仅仅知道变量的位置并不完全
enough. When we, if we know the value of x if we know the location for x, for example
足够的。当我们，如果我们知道x的值，如果我们知道x的位置，例如
or as, as important because we're going to get the value of x but we also have to
或者同样重要，因为我们要得到x的值，但我们也必须
know exactly when value is stored there and so store. Is going to be a mapping for
准确地知道值存储在那里的时间，因此可以存储。将会是一个映射
memory locations Values. These are the values that are actually stored in the
内存位置值。这些是实际存储在
memory so it's two levels of mapping. We associate with each variable and memory
内存，所以这是两个层次的映射。我们将每个变量和内存关联起来
location And then each memory location will have a value in it. So let's talk
位置，则每个内存位置都将具有一个值。所以让我们谈谈吧
about the notation that we're going to use for writing down the environment and the
关于我们将要用来写下环境和
store. So as we said, the variable environments have variables to locations
商店。所以就像我们说的，可变的环境对位置有不同的影响
and we're going to w rite that out. In the following way, we're going to just have
我们要把它写出来。在下面的方式中，我们将只需要
this as a list of variables and location pairs separated by columns and this
它是由列分隔的变量和位置对的列表，
environment for examples of variable a, is it location l1 And variable b is in
环境对于变量a的示例，是位置l1，而变量b在
location l2. And another aspect of the environment is that it's going to keep
位置L2。环境的另一个方面是它将保持
track of the variables that are in scalps and the only variables that will be
跟踪头皮中的变量以及将
mentioned in the environment are those currently in sculpted in the expression
环境中提到的是当前在表达式中雕刻的那些
that is being evaluated. Now as we said, stores map memory location to values and
这一点正在评估中。现在，正如我们所说的，存储将内存位置映射到值和
we'll also write out stores as lists of pairs. So in this case, the memory
我们还将以配对列表的形式写出商店。所以在这种情况下，内存
location l1 in the store contains the value five and the memory location l2
存储中的位置L1包含值5和存储位置L2
contains the value seven And we will also separate these pairs by an arrow. And just
包含值7，我们还将用箭头分隔这些对。然后就是
to make the stores look a little bit different from the environment so that we
为了让商店看起来与环境稍有不同，这样我们就可以
won't confuse the two. There's an operation on stores which is to replace of
不会把两者搞混的。在商店上有一项行动，要更换
value or update of value. So, in this case, we're taking the store s and we're
价值或价值的更新。所以，在这种情况下，我们取商店s，我们
updating the value at location l1 to b12 And this defines a new store s prime. So,
更新位置L1到B12的值，这定义了一个新的商店的素数。所以,
keep in mind here that the stores are just functions list in our model and so we can
请记住，商店只是我们模型中的函数列表，所以我们可以
define a new store by taking the old function or the old store has and
通过采用旧功能或旧存储具有AND来定义新存储
modifying it at one point. So this defines a new store as prime such if I apply s
在某一点上对其进行修改。因此，这将新存储定义为主存储，例如，如果我应用s
prime to the location l1, I get off the new value twelve and if I apply s prime to
到位置l1的素数，我得到新值12，如果将s素数应用于
any other location, any location different from l1 I get out the value that the store
任何其他位置，任何不同于L1的位置，我得到存储的值
held in s, sorry the value of the location in store s. Now in Cool we have more
保存在%s中，很抱歉商店%s中位置的价值。现在Cool中我们有更多
complicated values and integers. In particular we have objects and all the
复杂的值和整数。具体地说，我们有对象和所有
objects of course are instances of some class and we're going to need a notation
当然，对象是某个类的实例，我们需要一个表示法
for representing objects in our operational semantics. So we'll use the
用于在我们的操作语义中表示对象。所以我们将使用
following way of writing down an object. An object will begin with its class name.
遵循写下物体的方式。对象将以其类名开头。
In this case the class name x and it would be followed by a list of the attributes.
在本例中，类名x后跟属性列表。
In this case the class x has n attributes, a1 through an And associated with each
在这种情况下，类x具有n个属性，a1到an，并且与每个属性相关联
attribute will be the memory location whether an attribute stored so attribute
属性将是存储属性是否存储为属性的内存位置
a1 is stored location l1 up through attribute and which is stored at location
A1是通过属性向上存储的位置L1，并且存储在位置处
ln. And this would be a complete description of the object because we know
在。这将是对该物体的完整描述，因为我们知道
where in memory the object the object is stored. We can use the store to look up
在存储器中对象存储该对象的位置。我们可以用商店去查一下
the value of each of those attributes. There are few special classes in Kuhl that
每个属性的值。在库尔，很少有特殊的班级
don't have attribute names and we'll have special way overriding them. So integers
没有属性名，我们会用特殊的方式覆盖它们。所以整数
only have a value and, and that will be written as int with a single value in
只有一个值和，它将被写为int，在中只有一个值
parens, the value of the integer similarly for brilliance. They have a single value
括号，整数的值与Brilliance类似。它们只有一个值
true of false and strings have two properties, the length of the string and
TRUE OF FALSE AND字符串有两个属性，字符串的长度和
the sting constant. There's also a special value void typed object and we'll use the
刺痛常数。还有一个特殊的值void类型的对象，我们将使用
term void in our operational semantics to representative and briefly here, so void
术语在我们的操作语义中是无效的，在这里简单地表示，所以无效
is a, a special and that there are no operations that can be before and on void
是一个特殊的，并且没有可以在void之前和在void上的操作
except for the test is void. So, in particular, you can't dispatch the void
只是考试是无效的。所以，特别是，你不能把空位
even though it has typed objects that will generate runtime error. The only thing you
即使它具有将生成运行时错误的类型化对象。你唯一能做的就是
can do is to test whether the value is void or not. And concrete implementation
可以做的就是测试值是否为void。和具体实施
we typically use a null pointer which represent void. Now we're ready to talk
我们通常使用表示空的空指针。现在我们准备好谈谈了
about in more detail what the judgments will look like in our operational
关于我们行动中的判决将会是什么样子的更详细的信息
semantics so the context will consist of three pieces. The first piece is a current
语义学，因此上下文将由三部分组成。第一块是一股水流
self object. The second piece is the environment which is again the mapping
自我客体。第二部分是环境，也就是映射
from variables to the locations where those variables are stored and the third
从变量到这些变量的存储位置，第三个
piece is the memory, the store. The mapping from memory locations to the
片断是记忆，是商店。从内存位置到
values held at those locations, All right? So in some context, an expression e will
那些地方的价值观，好吗？因此在某些上下文中，表达式e将
evaluate to two things. First of all, e will produce a value so for example we saw
评估结果有两点。首先，e将产生一个值，例如，我们看到
before that the expressions seven + five would produce the value twelve, that's one
在此之前，表达式7+5将产生值12，也就是1
result to the evaluation. But the second thing is that we'll produce a modified
评估的结果。但第二件事是我们将生产一种改进型的
store. So the expression e maybe a complicated piece of code Maybe a whole
商店。所以表达式e可能是一段复杂的代码，也可能是整个
program is on the right and it might have a slight statements that update the
程序在右侧，它可能有一些更新
contents of the memory And so, after e is evaluated, there will be a new memory
因此，在计算e之后，将会有一个新的存储器
state that we have to represent and so s prime here represents the state of memory
我们必须表示的状态，所以这里的质数表示内存的状态。
after evaluation And now, those are couple of things here. First of all the current
经过评估，现在，这些都是这里的几件事。首先，当前
self object and the environment don't change. They are not changed by evaluation
自身物体和环境不变。它们不会因评估而更改
so which object is the self parameter to the current method and. Well, the mapping
那么哪个对象是当前方法的self参数，并且。嗯，这张地图
between variables and memory locations that is not modified by running a, running
在变量和内存位置之间，不能通过运行，运行
an expression and that makes sense, I mean, you can't update the self object in
表达式，这是有意义的，我的意思是，您不能在
Kuhl and we don't have access in, in any form to re-locations or variables stored
Kuhl和我们不能以任何形式访问重新定位或存储的变量
and so those two things are in variant. They don't they are variant under
所以这两个东西是不同的。他们没有，他们是变种的
evaluation. They don't change when you run a piece of code. However, the story does
评估。当您运行一段代码时，它们不会改变。然而，这个故事确实
change so the contents in the memory may be modified so that's why we need a store
更改以便可以修改内存中的内容，这就是我们需要存储的原因
for both before evaluation and after evaluation. And one more detail these
无论是评估前还是评估后。还有一个细节，这些
judgments of this form always has a qualification. That judgment only holds if
这种形式的判断总是有限制条件的。这一判断只有在以下情况下才成立
the evaluation of e terminates. So, if e goes in to infinite loop, then you're not
e的评估终止。所以，如果e进入无限循环，那么你就不会
going to get a value and you're not going to get a new store. So, this kind of the
将获得价值，而不会获得新的商店。所以这一种
judgment must always be read as saying that if e terminates, then e produces a
必须始终将判断理解为：如果e终止，则e产生一个
value v and a new store s prime. Summarize the results of evaluation is a value and a
值v和一个新商店的素数。总结评价结果是有价值的，也是有价值的
new store. And where the new store models, the side effects of the expression And
新开的店。以及哪里有新的商店模式，表达的副作用和
once again there are something don't change as a result of evaluation. And this
再说一次，有些东西不会因为评估而改变。还有这个
is actually important for compilation because we'll be able to take advantage of
对于编译实际上很重要，因为我们将能够利用
the fact that they don't change to generate efficient code so the variable
事实上，它们不会改变以生成高效的代码，所以变量
environment doesn't change, the value itself which object we're talking about
环境不变，值本身就是我们谈论的对象
doesn't change and notice here as another detail. That the contents of the self
没有改变，注意到这里是另一个细节。自我的内容
objects, the attributes inside the self object might change, they might get
对象，则Self对象内的属性可能会更改，它们可能会获得
updated but t he locations where the attributes are stored do not change. So,
已更新，但存储属性的位置不变。所以,
the layout of the object where the object stored doesn't change and that's all we're
存储对象的对象布局不变，这就是我们要做的
saying here, the actual contents of the object which of course is a part of the
在这里，对象的实际内容当然是
mapping of the store, those might get updated by evaluation. And also the
商店的地图，这些地图可能会通过评估进行更新。还有
operational semantics allows for non-terminating evaluations. That's the
操作语义允许非终止评估。这就是
last point here and so the meaning that the judgments only holds on the assumption
这里的最后一点，也就是判断仅仅基于假设的意义。
that the, that the expression actually completes.
那个，那个表达式实际上完成了。